I had a question like this: You say
у меня был такой вопрос Вот вы говорите
the Bashkirs want to separate, the Tatars want to
башкиры хотят отделиться татары хотят
separate, St. Petersburg is laughing to
отделиться санкт-петербург хохочет
separate, and in your understanding, what
отделиться и в вашем понимании что
will remain of Russia? What regions?
останется от России какие области ничего
Nothing at all? Otherwise, it will simply fall apart
ничего вообще а то просто распадётся
completely, yes. Well,
полностью да Ну
okay. Hello.
ладно Здравствуйте Вы
Where are you from in Russia?
откуда из России А город
What city is Belgorod? Yes.  well you are driving honestly And
какой Белгород Да ну вы гоните честно А
what are we driving Yes, everyone is just starting here
что мы гоним Да все просто тут начинают
I am from Belgorod from Belgorod just showing off
Я из Белгорода из Белгорода просто понто
now Belgorod or the exchange rate
сейчас Белгород или курс
they say pass passport No, no need Yes, I do
говорят пас паспорт Да не не надо Да я
so Believe I myself am from Vyborg in the
так Повер Я сам родом из Выборга
Leningrad region But I have been living in Brussels for
Ленинградской области Но живу в Брюсселе
18 years now  2 years will be a bit and you are
уже 18 лет через 2 года будет вато а вы
some kind of sportsmen,
какие-то спортсмены
sportsmen,
спортики
cool people, speak for yourself,
кайфарики за себя
let's have more rest Well, you are
говори отдыхаем больше Ну вы студенты
some kind of students or who Yes, yes, who are you
какие-то или кто Да да да на кого
studying to be a
учитесь на
mechanic Cool These are cars,
механиков Прикольно Это автомобили
locomotives What will you be mechanics, cars,
паровозы Что будете механи автомобили
automobiles, this is a vocational school or college or
автомоби этото ПТУ или колледж или
college
колледж
college A  how old are you 18 Well,
колледж А по сколько вам лет 18 Да ну
that one in the cap, in short, the one in the blue
вот этот в кепке короче что в синей
T-shirt, we're already thirty
футболке мы уже тридцатник
gosya in the fifth
гося в пятом
grade It seems you were in the fifth grade for the
классе Походу ты в пятом классе на
second year for about 10 years
второй год лет 10 оставался
Although in terms of mental development Anything is
Хотя по умственному развитию Всё может
possible I see maybe and what are those
быть я смотрю может быть а что за
beautiful stars behind your
красивые звёздочки у вас за
back the European Union This is no this is the flag of Bosnia
спиной Евросоюз Это нет это флаг Боснии
and
и
Herzegovina Wow, the country of Brussels
Герцеговины Ого ну страна Брюссель
Find brs this  the capital of Bosnia and
Находи брс это столица Боснии и
Herzegovina and this is our
Герцеговины и это наш
flag I don't know
флаг не зна
why they came from
а почему приехали из
Russia Listen listen yes Well I'm from the city of
России Слушай слушай да Ну я из города
Vyborg in the Leningrad region I come from
Выборг Ленинградской области родом
Listen Compare here in Bosnia and
Слушай Сравни у нас в босни и
Herzegovina the salaries are here and Compare in
герцеговине тут зарплаты и Сравни в
Russia you won't even think about going back
России даже не будешь думать вернуться
there how clean and for  money went I
туда как чисто и за денег поехали
see Well yes for a good life And what to
Понятно Ну да за хорошей жизнью А что
go And what to live in this choice or in Bel
ехать А что жить в этом выборе или в бел
how much do you have in Belgorod
сколько у вас в Белгороде
Well
зарплаты Ну
50 500 dollars is still necessary to work hard for
50 500 долларов это ещ надо от пахать на
them but not 500 already it's like 490 dollars
них да не 500 уже это типа 490 долларов
Yeah, screw it Look at  me I am a
Да ну нафиг Смотри у меня Я
university teacher I receive a small
университета Я получаю небольшую по
salary by our standards Yes it is  6,000 euros
нашим меркам зарплату Да это 6.000 евро
This is a little more
Это в переводе на российские чуть больше
than 600,000 rubles per month in Russian. What do you think?
чем 600.000 руб в месяц как ты думаешь
Does it make sense for me to go to
есть мне смысл есть ли мне смысл ехать в
Russia? And how much do you spend? For some
Россию А сколько вы тратите
reason, everyone from Russia tells me
жи все почему-то из России мне говорит
how much you spend, dude. Our phones
сколько тратите чувак У нас телефоны
are cheaper, cars are cheaper. Yes.  the products are the
дешевле машины дешевле Да продукты такие
same in price, the quality is better
же самые по цене качество лучше потому
because we have very strict control over
что у нас тут контроль очень чёткий за
this here, yes,
этим да на коммуналку на коммуналку идёт
15% more goes to utilities than in Russia, this is completely
на 15% больше чем в России это вообще
insignificant. Even when I pay all
ничтожно Я даже когда выплачиваю всю
the utilities, look, I pay the
коммуналку Да вот смотри я выплачу
utilities and go there. Yes,  I have
коммуналки там еду Да у меня остаётся
5,000 euros left I can invest in phones and
5.000 евро я могу себе на телефоны на
cars And so
автомобили инвестировать И так
on
дальше
yeah he's a teacher and a teacher is a
угу он преподаватель а преподаватель
university teacher Mitsubishi
университета Mitsubishi
Outlander what
Outlander какого
year what year what year d
года какого года год какой д
second taken from the showroom Yeah okay And
второго с салона взятый Да нормально А у
what kind of cars do you have
вас какие Тачки
we
мы
teach that's it  question when I lived in
учим вот в том-то и вопрос я когда жил в
Vyborg I when I was in Vyborg I
Выборге Я когда был в Выборге У меня
also had soris Yes I would not have a
тоже было сорис Да Бы
car I am figuratively speaking that there was no
машину не я образно говорю что не было
car on  I went by minibus When I
машины на маршрутке ездил Когда в
lived in Vyborg, in short, yes, they rose, what
Выборге жил пось короче да поднялись что
rose, rose Well,
поднялись поднялись
how do you say upe adj
Ну как сказать упе
Yes, he came to success, yes Well, of course,
прил Да пришёл к успеху да Ну конечно
damn Listen, I have My mom and dad
блин Слушай у меня У меня мама с папой
still live in Vyborg, my mom is
ещё живут в Выборге мама
a nurse, she's retired but still works as
медсестра она на пенсии но ещё работает
a nurse Yes, because  there aren't enough
медсестрой Да потому что не хватает
workers she has a pension Guess
рабочих пенсия у неё вот Отгадай
how much the pension is 15,000 not
сколько пенсия 15.000 не
18 much It's a big difference though
18 сильно Большая разница правда
dad didn't send help from here I don't know
бате не присылал отсюда помощь Я не знаю
how they would have survived and Mom still works
как бы они выжили и Мама ещё работает
at the same time Yes so that Well so that they could
при этом Да чтобы Ну чтобы ещё зарплату
have at least some kind of salary in short it's brutal
хоть какую-то иметь короче это жесть
now
сейчас
sneezed Be healthy Be healthy And
чихнул Будь здоров Будьте здоровы А у
your parents How much do they
вас родители Сколько
get 100 18 190 so on 108 190 he's
получают 100 18 190 так на 108 190 он
[ __ ] on shift unless he works hard everything's
бля на вахте разве что будет пахать всё
right but in Belgorod he
правильно ну а так в Белгороде он такой
won't earn that much this Bazaar no What about you they don't
не заработает это Базару нет Что там вас
take you from colleges to war
на войну не забирают из
no  and there they don't campaign
колледжей нет а там не агитируют
like I have a friend Well, like a friend
типа у меня знакомый Ну как знакомый
Odnoklassnik was in Vyborg Yes Sanya
Одноклассник был в Выборге Да Саня
Prokhorov, in short, the kid studied, a golden
Прохоров короче пацан учился золотая
head Yes, I'm so-so Well, I was a good student,
голова Да это я так себе Ну я хорошистом
like, yes I liked some
был типа да Я вот любил некоторые
subjects and the rest so-so and Sanya Prokhorov,
предметы а остальные так а Саня Прохоров
he stupidly went for the Gold Medal there, he
тупо он на Золотую медаль шёл там он
too I went to Bosnia and Herzegovina in
тоже я поехал в боснию и герцеговину в
Brussels Yes to work as a teacher and he
Брюссель Да преподавателем работать а он
he stayed in Leningrad Well, in
остался он в Ленинграде Ну в
St. Petersburg, he started working,
санкт-петербурге типа стал работать
went and in the second year, they
поехал и в д втором году Вот это его
took him, took him
взяли забрали
into the army, ZRO mobiles, and in the twenty-third
в армию мобили Зро и в двадцать третьем
year, near Bakhmut, in short, a drone
году под бахмутом короче ему Дрон
flew into his
прилетел в
head,
голову проте
so what do you think, does it make sense for me to
то как ты думаешь есть мне смысл
return to  Russia, yes, if Sanya
возвращаться в Россию да если Саню
Prokhorov was taken from the physics and mathematics
Прохорова типа вот взяли с физмат
department, like sent to die near
кафедры типа отправили сдохнуть под
Bakhmut, and
бахмутом и
that's
что вот
how it is. Trouble, do you have any acquaintances
так Беда у вас кто-то из знакомых есть
who
кто
died,
погиб
no. There are distant acquaintances, distant, but
нету Есть дальние знакомые дальний Но
who no longer communicated, and what happened to them?
которые уже не общались а что с ними
200 200 Well, it's clear  yes Cargo 200
случилось 200 200 Ну ясно да Груз 200
type together yes namely what
типа вместе да а именно что
happened someone in the tank  they shot him down there
случилось кого-то в танке подбили там
like that I know for one that they
вот так я за одного знаю что в танке
shot him down in a tank Well, this Sanya would have passed That is,
подбили Ну бы этому Сане прохо То есть
he is still there, a video was circulating on this
он есть ещё видео гуляло по этому
on telegrams Yes, because his mother
по телеграмам Да потому что мне его мама
showed me that the Ukrainians even laughed like
показывала что украинцы аж смеялись типа
yes, it turns out that the drone was catching up with him, he was running away
да его получается Дрон догонял он убегал
from the drone  runs runs And he
от дрона он бежит бежит И он
turns around and in short, right in his
разворачивается и короче Ему прямо в
face, like, his head flew off, in short, well,
лицо типа башка отлетела короче ну
damn, it was scary and mom was crying hysterically at first
блин стрёмно и мама сначала плакала в
Yes,
истерике была Да
she was still 3 months Then she recovered From
она ещё 3 месяца Потом отходила От
this, his little sister Well, she was 3 years
этого сестричка его Ну она на 3 года
younger, well, such a pretty
младше была ну симпатичная такая
girl, like, well, how  we like me with Sanya
девчонка типа ну как мы как я с Саней
Prokhorov were friends you know and her sisters
Прохоров дружил знаешь а её сестрички
A little left there to the point in short she
Немножко там левал к не то короче она
sit
посиди
and parents don't
а родители не
want they don't want they don't want Well that
хотите они не хотят они не хотят Ну то
is the thing is that mom she listened to
есть Дело в том что мама она наслушалась
like television that here in short like they
типа телевидение что тут короче типа там
hold these parades there  what are they Coca lo
эти парады проводят что они Кока ло
change something what if what And how are the
менять что-то а вдруг а что А как тут
friends here She at least lives Well, I
знакомые Она хоть живёт Ну вот я
send them money Yes  to help Here
присылаю им деньги Да чтобы помогать Тут
she has neighbors whom she has known there for
у неё есть соседи которых она знает там
30-40 years, so you understand They are already
30-40 лет так понимаешь Они уже там
grandmothers there, they all communicate there Well, that is,
бабушки все они там общаются Ну то есть
she is afraid that she will be left alone there and they
она боится что там останется одна и
dont
такое не
want this, its the same as you know, someone from the
хотят это так же как знаешь кто-то из
village comes to  city Yes, parents
деревни приезжает в город Да родители
stay in the village, they don't want to, and you
остаются в деревне они не хотят а вы
yourself are from Belgorod or somewhere else in the
сами из Белгорода или где-то тоже из
region. You just came to Belgorod. Well, from the
области Просто приехали в Белгород Ну с
region, because I see that this is
области потому что я смотрю что это
like a dorm. And where from? From the region, from
вроде как общага А откуда С области с
which
каких
areas? Old O Skol Old Skol Old
районов старая о скол старая скол старая
skol is a damn rich city, in short,
скол - это блин богатый короче город у
we had a classmate there from the old
нас одногруппница там была со старого
skol, she said that there was
скола она говорила что там короче
some kind of quarry there, that almost all
какой-то карьер что там чуть ли не всё
the iron in Russia was dug there, in short, in this
железо России копают короче в этом
quarry she said that there was like damn,
карьере она говорила что там типа блин У
her dad, in short, was some kind of  then this
неё батя Короче был каким-то этим
manager at this quarry is like not the most
заведующим на этом карьере типа не самый
important And in some management then
главный А в какой-то в менеджменте то
she said yes what is there who works
она говорила да что там кто работает вот
in this quarry then there clearly
в этом карьере то там чётко
has How are you there calmly they don't bomb
имеет Как там у вас спокойно не бомбят
you sometimes sometimes And like well what are the
вас бывает бывает А как типа ну что там
missiles there  they fly in as if  I live here in Brussels
ракеты прилетают как бы я в Брюсселе тут
peacefully I don't know how
спокойно живу я не знаю как
big and
летают большие и
small ones fly I didn't understand baba Well baba
маленькие вот эти не понял баба Ну баба
iga Drone is called big these are
ига Дрон называют большой такие в
mostly like this I mean baba Well I just
основном такие В смысле баба Ну я просто
don't understand them You can
не разбираюсь в них Вы можете в
look on the Internet Drone baba ega is
интернете посмотреть Дрон баба ега
called so so  what is it called well what
называется так так же называется ну что
does it do it's like a kamikaze or it
он делает он типа камикадз или он
drops
скидывает
something drops A drops I got it
что-то сбрасывает А сбрасывает понял
Like A got it that is a drone that
Типа А понял то есть это Дрон который
drags a heavy mine yeah Well yeah a heavy projectile
тащит тяжёлую мину да Ну да шный снаряд
someone smart like Found something like this
ктото умный типа Нашёлся вот такой
Wow Holy [ __ ] this is a
примерно Ух Ни фига себе вот это
hexacopter
гексакоптер
cool, it'll
классно прико человека
lift a person up Cool Oh, and
поднимет Прикольно А ну
this is what the Ukrainians are
ещё это вот это которую украинцы
launching at you,
запускают на вас
yeah, yeah, it's
да Ну да
tough, but it turns out like this, well,
жестк а а получается типа вот это ну
where are they like
куда они типа это
dumping this? Well, not even for
сбрасывают Ну даже не по стратегическим
some strategic reasons, but just residential buildings in the
каким-то моментам а просто жилые дома в
kindergarten, like this in
садике вот такое в
hospital And how do people feel about this
больнице А как люди относятся к этой
war? Probably everyone is already fed up with it. Of
войне уже задолбало наверное всех
course, I think from all sides,
Всё конечно я думаю со всех сторон она
everyone is already fed up with it, not just us. Well, I'm in
уже всем надоело не только нам Ну мне в
Brussels.  somehow I don't care at all you know like
Брюсселе как-то вообще пофиг знаешь типа
I live peacefully for myself I don't really
я себе спокойно живу мне я не сильно
get involved I didn't set up a VPN Ukraine
втягиваю я н ставил VPN Украина с
also communicated with Ukrainians how do you
украинцами тоже общался как вы
feel about me, a Russian UNO from Europe
относитесь ко мне русскому Уно с Европы
And they also say something like that there
Да и они типа там что-то так тоже
Well like you're in Europe  yes Bo I
говорят Ну типа ты в Европе да Бо я
say that I am Russian myself Yes I am from the
говорю что я-то русский сам Да я из
city of choice but I support ZSU I will
выбор городом но я поддерживаю зсу
donate to ZSU To drones Yes so that this
доначу На зсу На дроны Да чтобы вот это
well maybe by the way Sanya Prokhorov By the way I
ну может кстати Саню Прохорова Кстати я
donated to drones yes here too damn it
донатил на дроны да тут тоже блин
turns out I seem to donate to drones so
получается я вроде доначу на дроны чтобы
that  zsu Yes, so that zsu would drive these
на зсу Да чтобы зсу выгнала вот этих
occupiers out of Ukraine And my classmate
оккупантов из Украины А мой одноклассник
Sanya Prokhorov Yes, it turns out he is an occupier
Саня Прохоров Да он получается оккупант
and maybe his head was just smashed in by a drone
и может ему как раз бошку разбила дроном
that I donated to, I also thought damn Well, there
на который я донатил тоже думал блин Ну
is such a thing that drones
есть же такая штука что котора дроны
plant, you know Anti-anti-drone
садят б вы знаете Анти антидроновые
thing yes  they we can like well take
штука да они мы можем типа ну забрать
this drone reprogram and with this same
этот Дрон перепрограммировать и этим же
drone
дроном
can against their fiancs there is also Yes what is
может против их ихних же Же есть ещё
his name What is his name  Sorry,
Да как его зовут Как его зовут Извините
we forgot who's name is
мы забыли кого зовут
What's your name? We didn't introduce
Вас как зовут Так мы не представлялись
ourselves My name is Andrey A Andrey Nice to
Меня Андрей зовут А Андрей Приятно
meet you Nikita
познакомиться вас Никита
and Vitaly Nikita and Vitaly Yes Oh, damn, yes
и Виталя Никита и Виталя Да Ой блин да
Nikita and Vita are young guys I don't know
Никита и Вита молодые пацаны Я не знаю
Go somewhere in Europe They'll take you
свали где-то в Европу заберут вас тоже
to war too and  you will be like Sanya
на войну и будете как Саня
Prokhor with
Прохор с
Look when my salary is 6,000 euros
Смотри когда у меня зарплата 6.000 евро
Yes I can donate for drones for the ZSU Yes And what will they let
Да я могу донатить на дроны для зсу Да А
you donate there In short,
вы там что на донатить вам пустят Короче
like meat, run away like that and that's all
как мясо бежать типа и всё что
that the Ukrainian armed forces And what about the Don,
что збройны силы Украины А что Дона я
what about the dictator? In short, no
что диктатора поддерживать Короче не
on the contrary I think I think that look
наоборот Я считаю я считаю что смотри
this dictatorship needs to be overthrown yes When
эту диктатуру Надо скинуть да Когда не
Putin is gone when Ukraine drives
будет Путина когда Украина выбьет
Putin's troops out of its territory
путинские войска с со своей территории
yes then here in Russia they will start to overthrow
да тогда у нас в России начнут свержения
Putin and finally normal
Путина и наконец-то начнётся Нормальная
life will begin as we are the richest country Yes
жизнь как мы богатейшее государство Да
oil gold gas diamonds  we live in poverty
нефть золото газ алмазы живём бедно
Why does my mother receive a pension of 18,000
Почему моя мама получает пенсию 18.000
rubles in Russia 180 dollars yes  or there 170
руб в России 180 долларов да или там 170
euros and I in small Bosnia and
евро а я в маленькой Боснии и
Herzegovina in Brussels get 6000 euros
герцеговине в Брюсселе получаю 6000 евро
as a
как
teacher who takes all this
преподаватель кто забирает все эти
money can you tell me
деньги можешь мне сказать
Well it turns out oil gas gold diamonds
Ну получается нефть газ золото алмазы
they take for themselves and our people go in short
берут себе а людей наших идут короче
damn they throw war after war so that in
блин кидают войну на войну чтобы в
Ukraine in short they capture more  in short
Украину короче захватывали ещё короче
oil gold gas and everything is gone my Sanya
нефть золото газ и всё заш умер мой Саня
Prokhorov died for
Прохоров ради
what reason did you
чего бошку дроном
tear off his head with a drone physics and mathematics school
оторвала физико математическую школу
Zakan
Закан
University teacher in the richest country in
университета в богатейшей стране
the world This is a person's destiny such a destiny
мира Вот это судьба у человека судьба
Well okay probably Let's move on
такое Ну ладно наверное Пойдём мы дальше
Let's work I will I will all
Давайте работаем Я буду я буду все
work here I will  donate watch Don't
работать тут буду донатить смотрите Не
go to war because my Drone is somewhere Maybe
идите на войну бо где-то мой Дрон Может
I wouldn't want to donate to the ZSU
мне не хотелось бы чтоб я донатил на зсу
And good Russians That's how it killed
Да и хороших русских Вот так убивало оно
yes I want only bad ones Yes therefore
да Я хочу чтобы только плохих Да поэтому
don't go to war because you seem good Yes so
не идите на войну бо вы вроде хорошие Да
that you don't become  there bad because
чтобы не стали там плохими потому что
like Sanya Prokhorov
как Саня Прохоров
yes goodbye goodbye Oh listen
да до свидания до свидания О слушай
wait still wanted this wait This in
подожди ещё хотел это подожди Этот в
some kind of robe And you
халате какой-то там А вы
are getting it Yes, look, uh, guys from the
получается да смотри ээ мне вот Ребята с
Kursk region told me that Ukraine
Курской области рассказывали что Украина
captured part of the Kursk region, and from
захватила часть Курской области да а с
Belgorod I remember that
Белгородской Я помню что что-то в
Ukraine also went into the Belgorod
Белгород тоже Украина заходила туда в
regions or is this a fake And this is this is this
районы или это фейк А это это ещё Это
was it a long time ago or
давно было или
recently now Voronsky
недавно сейчас воронский
district And a long time ago or not Well damn they said I
район А давно или нет Ну блин говорили я
remember for a long time that something about the Belgorod
давно помню что что-то про Белгородскую
region we have watch we just have
область у нас смотри у нас просто
television well maybe you cha Yes there is
телевидение ну вас может ча Да там
some
какой-то
district Voronsky raion something like that it
район воронский раон как-то так
was called Voronsky Well  there somewhere as
называлось воронский Ну там где-то как
soon as it all began Well, drg came to us
только всё начиналось Ну дрг к нам
Or maybe it's like Partisan
заходило А может это типа Партизанский
everything, that is, they didn't capture Yes, the
всё то есть они не не захватили Да
territory about two years ago It was that they were
территорию года два назад Это было их
driven out on the same day because in the
выбили в тот же день потому что в
Kursk region yes It turns out that there have
Курской области да Получается что там
already been 4 months  how well the territory A from you
уже 4 месяца как ну территория А от вас
from Belgorod to the border
от Белгорода до границы
how much well
сколько ну
look
смот
where from Well to the nearest border of
откуда Ну до ближайшей границы
Ukraine at the moment lome 150
Украины на данный момент ломе 150
kilometers 150 damn it can do
километров 150 блин это могут дост
something roughly speaking
чем-то грубо говоря
yes At the moment we to no one  now they are not
да На данный момент мы никому сейчас не
needed at the moment in the sense Well in the
нужны на данный момент в смысле Ну в
sense that for some reason the world
плане что по городам мир
attacked the cities too they also
зачем-то же напали тоже они же так же и
hit the cities I am saying Alekseyevka that
бьют по городам же говорю алексеевку что
they hit
били
our moms what about me too Well I am this this
момы наш че я тоже Ну я вот вот это вот
this by the way I am also not  understood because
это кстати я тоже не понимал потому что
I asked the Ukrainians, yes,
я у украинцев спрашивал да ти по что
why in the Kursk region Yes, you attacked
зачем в Курской области Да вы напали на
peaceful villages and cities That's it They
мирные сёла и города Вот это Они мне
can't answer me either I say that
тоже не могут ответить Я говорю что
Russia No matter what, Russia has a
Россия Да как бы там не было Россия там
dictatorial regime there Yes, it just took
диктаторский режим Да она просто взяла
well  bombed Mariupol Bakhmut bombs
ну разбомбил Мариуполь бахмут бомбит
Kharkov yes And why on the Kursk region
Харьков да А зачем на курскую область
if there well like I I I can say Like
если там ну типа я я я могу сказать Типа
to divert from Eh how to say from
чтобы отвести от Ээ как сказать от
other front lines like to ease
других линий фронта типа чтобы ослабить
our tension on the borders
напряжение наше на границ
some like so that some troops
некоторые типа чтобы некоторые войска
come to Kursk so that it would be easier for
пришли в Курск чтобы было легче
them  got it got it that is it turns out uh we are
им понял понял то есть получается э мы
Russia Yes Bombed just there Mariupol
Россия Да Бомбила просто там Мариуполь
what is there
это что там
Kharkov I was making fun of
Харьков Я же издевался с
not a lick of a peep comment for Sanya Prokhorov
ни лак писка комент за Саню Прохорова
b what is your name Andrey
б как звать Андрей тебя
Vasily
Василий
Vasilyevich
Васильевич Вы
where are you from  And what did you hang this
откуда А что ты вот это повесил вот
on the back with what What do you want to show with this
сзади чем Что ты этим хочешь показать
sea
море
beach This is the beach the sea is worried once yes the sea is
пляж Это пляж море волнуется раз да море
worried the troll is normal They see they
волнуется троллю нормально Они видят
shout Slava no And everything everything everything is a bazaar I am from
кричат Слава нет А всё всё всё базар я с
Kursk Where are you
Курска Вы
from Belgorod
откуда Белгород
Belgorod It is because of you that we are now  in short, because
Белгород Это из-за вас нас сейчас короче
of us, and who gave it in short? In short, they
из-за нас а кто короче дал Короче они же
first got into your hands a couple of times, you didn't
сначала к вам залезли пару раз вы им не
let them. They realized that they could get in, they got in, and they came
дали Они поняли что можно лезть полезли
to us. Well, it's not us who are to blame,
попёрли к нам Ну так ну не мы ж виноваты
but those who regulate all this. And who signed up for
а те кто этим всем регулирует А кто вы в
territorial defense?  even though we have
тероборону записались хоть у нас
territorial defense organized now,
тероборона сейчас организована записаны
guys, we are all registered, we are all doctors, we are subject to military service. Well, the
пацаны все мы медики мы военнообязаны Ну
fact that you are not at
то что ты не на
war, I should be right. And why aren't you
войне я прям должен быть А ты почему не
at war,
на войне
wait. So what? Listen, you are doctors, you
подожди Ну и что Слышь вы медики вы
are not, but a student, you
нете а студент та
say you look like a grown man, that's all
говори выглядишь как взрослый мужик всё
I thought.  you say medic because there
я думал ты говоришь медик потому что
really isn't enough medics in Kursk
Медиков реально не хватает у нас Курске
in our Kursk hospital is overcrowded
у нас в Курске больница переполнены
of course yes they brought us
конечно да Нам тоже привозили
yours too And where in Belgorod they brought you straight to
ваших А куда в Белгород везли прям в
morgue in Orel I know I'm taking to Belgorod like they
морг в орл Я знаю везу в Белгород типа
didn't
не
take Well I don't
везли Ну не
know maybe something's wrong
знаю может что-то не
now in short you don't have any
то сейчас короче у вас типа тревог
air raid alarms There was recently we had
воздушных нету Есть недавно было у нас
three alarms today there was one P 5
сегодня три тревоги было одна была П 5
o'clock they
часов было
let in they let in BP Well what do you have  there this one
пускали пускали БП Ну что у вас там этот
where they have already entered Well look they are standing
куда по заходили уже Ну смотри они стоят
like My uncle tells me uncle I have VD
как Мне дядька говорит дядька у меня ВД
he says that they are standing
он говорит что они стоят
from the chickens there Kurchatov and Kursk ours have dug in
от кур там Курчатов и Курск наши окопали
very well because they will come Well that
очень хорошо потому что они придут Ну то
is they will not take Kursk they go there
есть они Курск не возьмут они там ездят
these villages In short  they have these mobile
эти сёла Короче у них мобильные эти
groups and they like today in one village
группы и они типа сегодня в одном селе
they went wild tomorrow in another and they do
покуралесил завтра в другом и они делают
something like that,
вот такую типа что
but in that they blew up the bridges,
их но в том что они мосты взорвали вот у
here is my uncle's Brigade They
меня дядькина вот эта Бригада Они через
crossed the river because they
речку переходили сем потому что
abandoned the pontoon crossings, that's why they
понтонные переправы покидали потому
blew it up  these four
взорвали эти четыре
bridges So
моста Так что
it's just awful and what year are you
есть просто ужас а вы какой курс
already second third
уже второй третий
fifth you somehow look older than
пятый ты как-то выглядишь постарше чем
second
второй
year to me
курс мне
18 Cool, are you on your own or somewhere? And you
18 Прикольно ты самол или где-то А
look 25 to 26 Wow, what's wrong with your
выглядишь на 25 на 26 Ого а что с
voice? Yes, I'm hoarse.
голосом Да я хрип
I realized that I'm hoarse. And what's wrong with your wheeze? Yes, I caught
Я понял что хрип А что хрип Да это
a little cold, I slept with the window open,
простудился немного с окном открытым
I
поспал
understood. Be careful. It's better for us not to get sick now,
понял Смотри осторожно Нам сейчас болеть
yes. And what about you?  Belgorod region refugees
да А у вас Белгородской области беженцы
are there
есть Есть
Of course they brought A well cheek cheek
конечно привезли А ну щекина
good Nigo
гоже Ниго
in short well I saw Well Kina not just
короче ну видел Ну кина не просто
shelling but in short they
обстреливают а Короче суджу они
took Sudzh yes Sudzh to us first that many of
взяли да суджу нам сначала что там много
ours
наших
died there knows I don't know I don't count
полегло знает я не знаю я же не считаю
But like the only thing that we have when  this is
Но типа единственное что у нас когда вот
how it all started We thought that they,
это всё началось Мы думали типа что они
like you, like went into some
как вот у вас типа зашли в какое-то село
border village and like took photos They
приграничное и типа фотки делают нам
told us that everything was fine, everything was fine
говорили что всё нормально всё нормально
Then like evacuation in short x
Потом типа эвакуация короче х
RAYON kon I just wanted to
РАЙОНО кон Я только у тебя хотел
ask you this is what they really say
спросить вот это это реально говорят
earlier I'll tell you this I was in the d vrom
раньше вот скажу так мне в д вром было
on Crimea Donetsk Lugansk are they No I'll
на Крым Донецк Луганск есть они Нет я
tell you honestly I even when there was shelling
честно скажу Мне даже когда вот обстрелы
Belgorod region Well, we were worried, but
Белгородской области Ну мы переживали но
by and
по
large,
большому у
this is when a drone can fly in
это ког может беспилотник прилететь
when they shell the suburbs of Kursk with Grad, they
когда обстреливают они градом пригород
shelled them, they already
Курска обстреляли есть у них уже
have it, and you already think to yourself
дотягивает и ты уже такой думаешь себе
when you have an alarm three or four times a day, its
когда у тебя три-четыре раза в день
completely different, and now I
тревога уже совсем подругому и я Теперь
understand that  Moscow also
понимаю что Москва также она и нас и вас
doesn't understand us and you either, Muscovites, like
тоже так само не понимает москвичи типа
they think, well, there's something there, in short, somewhere there's
они думают ну там что-то короче где-то
a war, something's being done, but when you're
война что-то справляется но когда ты
far away, we thought the same about Belgorod, like,
далеко Вот мы про Белгород также думали
what kind of shelling of Belgorod, but
Ну типа какой там обстрел Белгорода да
they're far away, it seems  And now you understand
они далеко вроде А теперь ты понимаешь
that 20 km anyway there are
что 20 км всё равно
arrivals like this I already met
прилёты есть такая я уже вот я встречал
these guys from Donetsk too and I say It's because
этих с Донецка пацанов тоже и говорю Вот
of you that we kind of
из-за вас это на часть мы типа за вас
got involved for you we turn out not to have helped them
впряглись мы получается не им не помогли
yet Kursk region We are now so what
ещё курскую область Нам сейчас так что
I honestly say to him if they said that
нем честно я говорю если бы сказали тот
Donetsk Crimea leave Crimea he can at least
Донецк Крым оставить Крым у него хоть на
go to the sea Donetsk
море можно ездить донецки
Lugansk Here you are from Donetsk Lugansk there is
Луганск Вот тебе с Донецка Луганска есть
sense he is not needed yes
толк он не нужен да
there is
есть
Oh
Ой у
I had a classmate, he was in the first days of
меня Одноклассник был то он в первые дни
his life Well, he was like a professional soldier,
сво Ну он типа профессиональный военный
he was in the first days of his life, in short, he
был он в первые дни сво короче под
died near Mariupol and there are people like him Do
мариуполем погиб и таких как он есть
you have acquaintances who
У тебя есть знакомые
died,
погибшие
there are at
есть двое
least two young guys, yes, they were 18 to
минимум молодые пацаны да было по 18 по
20 years old And how are they  got to
20 лет А как они попали на
war I don't know Something happened to them in their lives
войну Я не знаю У них там что-то в жизни
they eventually came to an agreement with someone
произошло они в итоге там с кем-то
they
договорились их
were taken there young one had his hand
взяли там молодые одному руку гранаты
torn off by a grenade now he's disabled It's
оторвало сейчас инвалид
funny And what did he
Прикольно А что он типа неправильно
throw the grenade incorrectly No he's a
кинул гранату Нет он
civilian he got the grenade the igniter the
Гражданский гранату достал запальник
igniter at  a man without an arm exploded in his hands
запальник у него в руках взорвался
Well, this Well,
человек без руки Ну это Ну это
of course you don't know this Yes Like if you don't
конечно не шаришь Да Типа если ты не
know the safety precautions of
шаришь техника безопасности
my uncle's business in short, in this in
дела моего дядьки короче в этом в
GRU a drone hit a guy in the shoulder in short
Гру мужику дроном короче в плечо попало
and like the shoulder and shrapnel went to the head, they
и типа плечо и осколки пошли в голову то
didn't save Well there without  there was an option yes
не спасли Ну там без варианта было да
there is such a neighbor in our house like there is
есть такое сосед в нашем доме типа есть
Well I don't know he also served in some kind of service but
Ну я не знаю он тоже какой-то служил но
you will understand either he was a contract soldier or he
поймёшь или он контрактник или мобили
was called up for mobile you won't ask like that  the
званый был ты так не будешь спрашивать
guy without a leg is walking now don't come and
чувак без ноги сечас ходит ты не подой
ask Tell me
спро Расскажи
in short they are wandering around that he fought somewhere near
короче шатаются что он где-то под
Bakhmut
бахмутом типа воевал
but we don't know whether he was Wagner or not
а не знаем или Вагнер или не Вагнер Так
So do you have Chechens now
что А у вас чеченцы есть сейчас это
or should there be recently
или должны быть вот недавно
this this Adin in short yes we have  the very first
этот этот Адин короче да у нас первые же
days they recorded this Aladdin tiktok that
дни они записывал этот Аладин tiktok что
everything was fine everything was under
всё нормально всё под
their control when it was calm they were
контроль их когда вот спокойно было они
with us in clubs in cafes in short
у нас вот в клубах в кафешках короче
everywhere there was a smell of fried
всюду были как жареным запахло
bearded men
бородатых
all he is not to you in
всё он же не к вам в
Belgorod who knows yes And like
Белгород кто его знает да А типа
oil depots not  oil depots not like in Rostov there is
нефтебазы не нефтебазы не как в Ростове
no oil depot but at the gas stations at the
нефтебазы нет но по заправкам по
gas stations Well they knock out you see they
заправкам Ну они же выбивают видишь они
took this terrorist
взяли это террористическую такую типа
tactic like knock out our energy system
тактику типа выбивать энергосистему нашу
like so that we don't
типа чтобы мы бензина не
have gasoline she Becky to all the
имели ше Беки на все
gas stations And how do people
заправки А как люди
fill up I don't
заправляются Я не
know In the
знаю В
sense Well maybe  there were some supplies there.
смысле Ну может там какие-то запасы были
That's how all the gas stations I know
Вот так вот все заправки которые я знаю
had them there. Well, how? Well, even if there are some
там были их Ну а как Ну даже если есть
supplies how to refuel if gas stations No
запасы как заправиться если заправки Нет
I don't know
я не знаю
Well like I understand that even if in short
Ну типа я понимаю что если даже короче
several if they work you can have a
несколько если работают можно там
queue there but if there are none at all how do people
очередь но если вообще нет как люди
survive Maybe there
выживает Может куда-нибудь
is somewhere What do we have there nearby
есть Что у нас там рядом
Voznesenovka Maybe there maybe in some
вознесеновка Может там может в каких-то
villages on
сёлах на
gas stations well I thought that they in the
заправках ну я там считал что они в
Belgorod region also want to
Белгородской область тоже что-то хотят
break through something they break through somewhere on the border
прорваться прорываются где-то на границе
Yes they always want
Да они всегда хотят
but like from you to the border there is 20
а вот типа от вас до границы там что 20
km yes or
км да или
how much well that's if you look at the chic
сколько ну это если шики на
Well I mean  if they
смотреть Ну имею в виду если они
break through like how do you like well you
прорываются типа как вам типа ну у вас
have some algorithm How do you act
есть какой-то алгоритм Как вы действуете
you have to leave or what does not tell you anything
вы должны выехать или что вам ничего не
so if they break through
рассказывает так если они прорываются
they koch in a day 20 k generally just
они коче в день 20 к вообще просто
pass Well that summer when there was a
проходят Ну вот тем летом когда была
mass evacuation of Shiben at  I
массовая эвакуация шибена у меня там
just had a girl I knew there, she told
просто знакомая девочка она рассказывала
no one anything, those who could just left in their cars.
никому ничего просто по машинам уехали
Yes, but Shebekino is small. And
кто смог Да но Шебекино оно маленькое А
how can Belgorod evacuate if everything is in
как Белгороду эвакуироваться если все
the groin, it will just be terrible. Well,
лону тож просто будет жесть Ну
yes, because it turns out like
да потому что у нас типа получается как
we have it with  Sudzhansky district also
у нас с суджанского района тоже
evacuated the governor says Yes they carried out a
эвакуация губернатор говорит Да провели
planned evacuation That's how people in short
плановую эвакуацию Вот так люди короче
who got in with whom then they left like and even
кто с кем садился ту выезжали типа да и
then in short not everyone left not everyone left
то короче не все выехали не все выехали
because then they started shelling
потому что они потом начали обстреливать
the road like they blocked the road with
дорогу типа перекрыли типа дорогу
shelling and that's it people were already afraid to
обстрелами и всё уже люди боялись
leave a lot  there is something left
выезжать много осталось
there
там есть
It's you in
такое Это вы в
the dorm
общаге
yes what's there guys Hello Yes by I'm
да что там пацаны Привет Да по
greeting with the guys still Who's there
Приветствую с пацанами ещ Кто там
greet
приветствуйте
yes we're here we're listening attentively there I'll
да мы тут мы слушаем внимательно туда я
greet in the eyes like Bro with
поприветствуем в глаза как Братуха с
Bro Yes we're just with a snit in naked
братуха Да мы просто с сница во голый
naked you sit yes Well yes at  here is one of us
голый сидишь да Ну да у нас вот один
who is a
который
little hung up I say boy Yes
лю завис немножко говорю пацанчик Да
now I developed boy damn caught a cold
сейчас развила пацанчик блин простыл
really there
реально там
make some tea with raspberries Yes with raspberries
чай с малинкой сделайте Да с малинкой
now he will recover it's a matter of time
сейчас выздоровит вопрос времени
yes So yes you take this tea with
да Так что да ты возьми это чаю с
raspberries somewhere drink Yes They will
малиной где-то попей Да
already come in short they will start throwing to you
Уже придут короче начнут тебе кидать
in short  and you will
короче а ты будешь
wheeze Glory to Ukraine come on let's give you there
хрипеть Слава Украине давай дай вас там
Come on let's do it normally
Давай давайте нормально пообщаемся
let's chat Guys, let's chat, let's chat without any aggression at all,
Пацаны давай давайте давайте вообще без
we'll start with bad phrases
агрессии мы мы начинаем с плохих фраз
because we'll get worked up if we start on the expensive side,
потому что нас кипат если мы по дорогому
let's chat, I understand, I
начинаем Давайте пообщаемся понял Я
generally communicate normally, how old are you,
вообще нормально общаюсь сколько вам лет
and 18, yes, well, yes, 18, yes, oops, I'm from the city of
а 18 да Ну да 18 да опа Я из города
Khmelnitsky, where are you from? We're from the city  Ufa about
Хмельницкий Вы откуда Мы из города Уфы о
Bashkortostan Yes he himself I was born in Ufa
Башкортостан Да он сам я Я родился в Уфе
Wow but I was 2 years old and Rodite 2 years old
Ух ты но мне было 2 года и Родите 2 года
my parents moved to Ukraine then
было мне родители переехали в Украину то
I don't even remember
я не помню там даже
anything there and for what reason they moved The
ничего а по какой причине то переехали
Soviet Union was Yes they
Советский Союз был Да они там там
worked there there
работали там
worked Pony And what do
работали Поня А чем обща у
Finns have in common? Just like that, kindly, without
Фин просто Да просто так по доброму без
aggression. Russian Pony When Bashkartastan
агрессии русс Поня Когда башкартастан
becomes free, will you stay to live in
станет свободным останетесь жить в
Bashkartastan or will you go there to Moscow,
башкартастан или поедете там в Москву
for example, how to understand free? I think I
например как понять свободную Я вроде
can from Bashkan Well, in the sense of declaring
могу из башкана Ну в смысле объявить
independence like Kazakhstan
независимость как Казахстан
Azerbaijan who wants to  us
Азербайджан кто хочет у нас
Announce Well
Объявлять Ну руски
Russians Russians don't want Bashkors and Tatars
рус вот русские не хотят башкор и татары
want yes
хотят да
Well maybe  yes I by the way I met you
Ну может быть да Я кстати встречал
know people who want to think about
знаешь людей которые хотят думают о
independence Noni with deep
независимости Нони с глубоких
skies di yes yes it turns out
ские ди есть есть получается о
only villagers think about independence No
независимости думают только селюки Да
no I'm not talking about that I'm talking about my
нет Я не об этом Я говорю о своём
observation I'm not saying anything at all Let them do what they
наблюдении ято вобще ничего не говорю
want Let them
Пусть хотят как Пусть как хотят так и
do what they want but  I would probably rather stay in
делают но я лучше останусь наверно в
Russia than in a separate Bashkortostan
России нежели в отдельном Башкортостане
Well, yes, well, that is, you will leave
Ну да ну то есть ты получается выедешь
independent Bashkortostan for
из независимого башкартастан на
the territory of Moscow Yes, somewhere, well, I will
территорию там Москвы Да где-то ну я
most likely leave in any case, a
скорее всего уеду в любом случае более
larger city in Russia, this is in any case
крупный город Росси у это в любом случае
dependent Probably everything-  so I will move
зависимости Наверно всё-таки я перееду
Yes to another city in Russia to
Да в другой город России в
which Well to Saint Petersburg San So Saint
какой Ну в санкт-петербург Сан так Сант
Petersburg will also declare independence
Петербург объявит тоже о независимости
it will be the region of Ingria Yes And why should he
это будет регион ингрия да А зачем ему
Declare independence Well it is
Объявлять о независимости Ну это же
originally Russian it is originally Russian originally
искон русский он искона русский искона
Swedish city originally Swedish
шведский город исконно шведский
city Peter I  not Peter after he
город Пётр I не Пётр пе после того как у
occupied this territory from the Swedes Yes he
шведов эту территорию оккупировал Да он
took there began to ra this Swedish fortress
взял там начал ра эту шведскую крепость
and made a city further And so it is from time immemorial
и сделал город дальше А так это искона
Swedish lands have always been icons of Swedish
шведские земли отродясь иконы шведские
lands but since there are Swedes living in
земли но раз там Швед живут в
St. Petersburg No now there are now people
санкт-петербурге Нет сейчас там сейчас
living there like not only Swedes but different
там живут типа не только шведы а разные
Like people Well I'm talking about this there but this is a
Типа люди Ну я об этом гово там но это
historical region of Ingria that
исторический регион ингерманландия то
is St. Petersburg will be an independent
есть санкт-петербург будет независимой
Ingria Yes here  the port city will
ингри Да вот портовый город будет себе
live normally You to Peter Tell me
нормально будет жить Ты Питеру Вот скажи
what Why does Ingria need to be independent
что Зачем независимая ингрии
You I yes You know that Ingria is a
ты я да Вы в курсе то что ингрия - это
small region on the outskirts of Pite it is not the
маленькая область на окраине Пите это не
whole Leningrad region I
вся Ленинградская область я ещё раз
say again you already know what Ingria is
говорю ви ты уже знаешь что такое ингрия
super I know  what is it And have you heard like a
супер Я знаю что такое А ты слышал типа
song by Oxxxymiron like Ingria will be
песню Оксимирона типа ингрия будет
free when one person says
свободной когда один человек говорит
some pretty strange ideas
какие-то достаточно странные иде это
does that mean he
разве означает
was one of those who voiced it
был одним из тех кто озвучил это
publicly And do you know that the referendum for the
публично А ты знаешь что референдум за
independence of Ingria took place in the
независимость ингрии проходил в
Russian Federation it was
Российской Федерации его
dispersed by Ingria as soon as  The FSB
разгонялась ингрии как только ФСБ типа
will be covered there, and then when the Ukrainian
накроется там да вот как украинские
troops get somewhere, it's
войска дойдут где-то Поближе это
all closer. But you say that Bashkiria  it
всё А вот вы говорите то что Башкирия
will be free that the Tatars also want to
будет свободно то что татары тоже хотят
separate those Petersburg too Listen
отделиться те Петербург тоже так Слушай
so Tatarstan look Tatarstan Well I'll
так Татарстан смотри Татарстан Ну я себе
explain to myself I'm the eldest don't interrupt the elders
объясню я старшей не перебивай старших
don't interrupt the elders look Tatarstan
не перебивай старших смотри Татарстан
Tatarstan back in the second year held a
Татарстан ещё в дено втором году провёл
referendum on independence
референдум о независимости
look I had such a question Here you
посмотри у меня был такой вопрос Вот вы
say  the Bashkirs want to separate, the Tara
говорите башкиры хотят отделиться тары
want, St. Petersburg wants to separate and
хотят санкт-петербург хочет отделиться и
in your understanding what will remain of
в вашем понимании что останется от
Russia, what regions, nothing, nothing
России какие области ничего ничего
at all, it will simply fall apart completely, yes,
вообще просто распадётся полностью да Ну
well, okay, yes, and how will this happen at all, here is
ладно Да а как это произойдёт вообще вот
what your plan of action is, it
какой у вас там план действий так
will happen, look, I explain historically,
произойдёт смотри объясняю исторически
just like  what happened to the Russian
так же как произошло с Российской
Empire and the Soviet Union they
империей и советским союзом они
got involved in a war they couldn't stand it
ввязались в войнушку не выдержали
economically military and politically they
экономически военны и политически
fell apart the Russian Empire
развалились Российская империя
fell apart later that year the
развалилась дальше в дено м году
Soviet Union and now the third
Советский Союз и сейчас проходит третий
stage of the collapse of this Russian Empire is going through the
этап распада вот этой Российской империи
Russian Federation should finally
Российская Федерация должна окончательно
fall apart and all this is logic you
развалиться и всё это логика Такая
understand everything  empires there was the
понимаешь все империи вот там была
Austro-Hungarian  it fell apart and
австро-венгерская развалилась так и
here and you think that Russia is an Empire for us
тут а вы считайте у нас Россия - это
Well, that is, we have a Monarch
Империя Да ну то есть у нас есть Монарх
there, no, I will say, look, you actually have a
там нет я скажу смотри у вас фактически
Monarch Yes, actually a Monarch,
Монарх Да фактически Монарх
here is Russia Look, here is how the
вот Российска Смотри вот как
Austro-Hungarian Empire fell apart Yes, it
австро-венгерская Империя развалилась Да
fell apart, new national
развалилась начали новые национальные
states began, for example
государства например появилось
the state of Czechoslovakia appeared, then it
государство Чехословакии дальше оно
fell apart into the Czech Republic and Slovakia, so
развалилось на Чехию и Словакию так
Yugoslavia, for example, yes, there was such a
Югославия например да вот было такое
state, Serbia also fell apart,
государство тоже развалилось там Сербии
and so on. Yes, that's what's happening
и так дальше Да вот то самое происходит
with the Russian Federation,
с Российской Федерацией отвалилась
Finland, Poland, Ukraine, and so on fell apart.
Финляндия Польша Украина и так дальше
Then the Soviet Union took over this Ukraine a little bit.
Потом Советский Союз захватил немножко
Yes, the Soviet Union  The Union in
эту Украину Да вот Советский Союз в
the year Denom fell apart into the Republics Yes
Деном году развалился на Республики Да
independent and now there is a decline of the Russian
независимые и сейчас идт спад Российской
Federation Look Here you do
Федерации Смотри Вот у вас Ты же
Agree that you already have
Согласись что у вас уже русских стаёт
fewer Russians non-Russians more and more
меньше не русских всё больше
true
правда
Russian Russian Federation Islam is
Российская Российская Федерация ислами
growing very
зру ется очень
strongly yes That is
сильно да То есть
you even If you compare with  European,
вы даже Если сравнивать с европейскими
conditionally German, as it were You understand,
условно немецкими как бы Сами понимаете
large cities there Moscow St. Petersburg
крупные города там Москва санктпетербург
No  there's not so much everything is like that there's just
Нет там не так много всё так там всё как
a lot of everything You look at the schools in the
раз очень много Ты посмотри по школам в
schools Russian children are already
школах Русских детей уже
a minority Well I wouldn't say in
меньшинство Ну не сказал бы на самом
fact not everywhere as well
деле вот далеко не везде как ну
as a schoolchild who has just graduated I wouldn't say
как вышедший школьник условно не сказал
conditionally Even here it's not Russian Well no  I will
бы условно Даже у нас не русская Ну не
accept the Russian Republic We didn't have a
приму русская республика У нас не было
large number of Islamic
прямо большого количества исламских
Children Look again at you Well
Детей ещё раз смотри ещё раз у вас Ну
if in your Bashkortostan Russians
если у вас в Башкортостане русские
only make up a third
только треть составляют
Why
Почему треть у
don't we have a third Look where 70% of Russians are in
нас нет Ты посмотри где 70% русских в
Bashkortostan What
Башкортостане что ты
did you come up with Let's do a census on Google 30  % there
придумал Давай на Гугле перепись 30% там
you are there 30 Bashkorto 30
вас там по 30 башкорто по 30
Tatars nikah
татары никах
samples now Well, here are 4000 people Russian
проб сечас Ну вот 4000 человек русских
12 Bashkirs
12 башкир
I read in Bashkartastan Take Take
почитаю в башкартастан Возьми Возьми
Bashkartastan and the
башкартастан да
population Wikipedia is a reliable source
население Википедия надёжный источник
here is the ethnic composition ethnic
вот национальный состав национальный
composition
состав
And so let's see and Russian 35%
А так давайте посмотрим а русский 35%
Bashki 20% Tatars Mishars 5  % 7% aunt  Maritsa
башки 20% татар мишары 5% 7% тетя марицы
5% Ukrainians 3% well
5% украинцы 3% ну как-то
somehow again how much do you have how much do
так ещё раз сколько у тебя сколько у
you have in total Well that is we have
тебя в сумме получилось Ну то есть у нас
Nana percent 100% I am talking about percentages
Нана процентов 100% Я говорю о процентах
now well How many Russians are in
сейчас ну Сколько русских в
Bashkortostan
Башкортостане
35% this is the majority yes If you
35% это это большинство да Если
compare with  other nationalities
сравнивать с другими национальностями
the majority is 50% P.S. about why Well in
большинство - это 50% ПС о почему Ну в
such a case
таком слу у на
where did you
куда
disappear everything came back I just
пропали всё вернулась Я просто страниц
connected the pages so read the numbers
подключил так ещё раз прочитай числа
you voiced again again come on
которые ты озвучиваешь ещё раз давай
Russian how many without problems come on 35%
русский сколько без проблем давай 35%
Russian 15 Bashkir Bashkir Yes 20% Tatar
русских 15 башкир башкир Да 20% татар За
What year are you reading this for? What year did you
какой ты год это читаешь За какой год ты
open the national composition table in Wikipedia?
открыл в Википедии табличку национальный
Yes, that's right, and you read the first column.
состав да верно и читаешь первую графу
Yes, by the way, you were right about this.
Да вы правы кстати были насчёт этого
Because I was really looking at the
Потому что я смотрел действительно за
Old Year. 1920. You said 100 years
Старый год 1920 год ты говорил 100 лет
ago. Now look. Now
назад теперь смотри сейчас теперь у
we have  36% Yes now we have 37.5 Russians
нас 36% Да теперь у нас 37,5 русских
20% Tatars oh 20
20% татар ой 20
where  Wikipedia 202 2020 I open Look
где Википедия 202 2020 Я открываю Смотри
I open this Wikipedia table 37.5
Я открываю эту табличку Википедии 37,5
Russians this is for Twentieth year still
русских это за Двадцатый год ещё
yes1
да1
these Barts 24 Tata this is for for there is
этих бартов 24 Тата это за за есть
a census there are even fewer
перепись там ещё меньше
Russians I don't know I haven't seen but
русских не знаю не видел но
why The point is that look I told you so
почему Суть в том что смотри я тебе так
there are 30% Russians there, that's
и сказал русских там 30% так и есть
true,
правда
35% of the rest are all non-Russians,
35% остальные все не русски
Rukh has a maximum of two children in
у Рух о максимум двое детей может быть в
school, maybe more Russians than
школе больше Русских чем
non-Russians, I'm telling you about my
нерусских я вам говорю о своих
personal ones. Because you look at the Tatars and
личных Потому что ты смотришь на татар и
think that they are Russian. Well, Russian
думаешь что они русские Ну русские
Tatars are  the phenomenon is quite
татары - это явление достаточно
widespread the essence In this you divide the
распространённое суть В этом Вы делите
national
национальный
composition into Russians and non-Russians
состав на русских и нерусских сть
Well that is to say look Russia is already becoming non-
Ну то есть смотри Россия уже стаёт не
Russian Well listen statistics if you
русской Ну слушайте статистика если
look at
смотреть
statistics Has a lot really changed
статистику Неужели много чего поменялось
1920 35% Russians 202 37% Russians
1920 год 35% русских 202 год 37% русских
Where does it become non-Russian  Russian
В каком месте она становится не русской
again Well, I am Bashkartastan, so
ещё раз Ну вот я башкартастан значит
look at how much you have  children of the Tatars of the
смотри у вас сль сколько детей у татар у
Bashkortos and How many children do
башкорто и Сколько детей у
Russians have Well, let's say that Russians on
русских Ну ну вот допустим у русских в
average even if you look at this room
среднем даже если смотреть по этой комна
Russian people have two children in a family
у русских людей по два ребнка в семье
two is not an average but a maximum of
два не в среднем а максимум
two No I wouldn't say this is the average
два Нет не сказал бы это сред
temperature in the ward On average  two
температура по палате В среднем два
Let's be honest That is, if
Давайте будем чест То есть если у
one of the Russians has no children, then
кого-то из русских нет детей то у
another Russian has four children Yeah, right, I
другого русского четыре ребёнка Да ну я
said the average temperature of the floor
гово средня температура пола
Aru maybe Come on, tell me, how many children do those who are
Ару може Давай скажи вот у тех которые у
sitting in your room have, your
вас в комнате сидят скоко детей ваших
parents two people two people two  a
родителей два человека два человека два
person is all I said two is the
человека всё Я же сказал два - это
maximum Who says that it is the maximum I
максимум Да кто говорит что максимум Я
say the average in the ward is not the average a
говорю средне по палате это не средне
person two people four people
человек два человека четыре человека
look No just three and four No
смотри Нет как раз трёх и четырёх Нету
Two is the maximum and many do not have children I
Два - это максимум а у многих нет детей
am telling you that the average Well okay  ok
вам говорю что сре Ну ладно хорошо
let's say let's not argue about this
допустим Давайте не будем спорить на эту
now because three times more people are
пер теперь бо втрое да большинство людей
non-Russians Yes, they are recorded as Russians in the census
нерусских Да в переписи записывают как
Well, this just says that
Ну это как раз таки говорит о том что
they are counted as no This says that they are
они причисляют к нет Это говорит о том
doing the same as they did in the Soviet Union  that it is not fashionable to be non-Russian And that
делают что не русским быть не модно Да и
is why people sign up like that then one
поэтому люди пока записываются так потом
moment and they say no I am Tatan I am
момент и они говорят нет я тотан я
Bashkort and so
башкорт и так
on in Russia in Russia look in Russia
дальше в России в России смотри в России
in recent years already How many Tajiks
за последние годы уже Сколько таджиков в
live in Russia now 3
России сейчас живёт 3
mlkh many
млх много
from
с
Uzbeks Tour and  so far that is Well
узбеков Тур и так даль то есть Ну да у
yes we have well we have national
нас ну у нас национально
multinational countries more I'll
многонационально страны больше я тебе
tell you Look in Russia according to statistics there are
скажу Смотри в России по статистике
more mosque parishioners than
прихожан мечетей больше чем прихожан
church parishioners Oh what statistics are these
церквей Ой это какая статистика ну-ка
come on where are these statistics Yes
давайте это где такая статистика Да
Look in Russia in Russia there are
Посмотри в в России в России прихожан
mosque parishioners  more than
мечети больше чем прихожан
church parishioners Russia is a Muslim
церквей Россия - мусульманская
country and church parishioners Well, let's
страна а и прихожане церквей Ну давайте
if we move on to the interethnic
если мы переходим на межнациональный
issue I didn't get it right now but the very fact that the
вопрос я сейчас не вбил но сам факт что
Bible says Let your right hand
в Библии сказано Пусть твоя правая рука
not know what your left hand says what your
не знает что говорит что делает твоя
left hand does And in Islam it is said that
левая рука А в исламе сказано что
I grow  boards show your religion and
отращиваю борды свою религию показывай и
how would you enter my my favorite topic
как бы вы на мою мою любимую тему
Well, that's not the point Let's have
вступили Ну суть не в этом Давайте яб ку
your apple  favorite Topic you in religion shari
твоя любимая Тема ты в религии шари
religion I'm just a Christian Christian
религии Я просто христианин христианин
The thing is that I
Дело в том что я
end me site please say
оканчиваются мне сайт пожалуйста сказать
let's look so we either talk eye to
давай так смотри мы либо говорим глаза в
eye or I switch it I
глаза либо я переключаюсь это я в чёрный
won't look at the black square You told me to look at the
квадрат не буду смотреть Вы мне сказали
statistics so look Well
посмотреть статистику так смотри Ну
Take it  Take the phone from a colleague and look
Возьми Возьми телефон у коллеги и смотри
like
типа
my colleagues are in the kitchen now Well
мои коллеги сейчас на на кухне Ну так
then you'll find it later let's turn it on like
тогда потом найдёшь давай включай типа
so I can see you in the eyes or In short I'm
чтобы я тебя в глаза видел или Короче я
switching with a black square I won't
переключаюсь чёрным квадратом я не буду
talk Okay let's go let's go I
говорить Хорошо давайте давай я меня
can see me Yes it's clear that look I'm finishing
видно Да видно что смотри я я заканчивал
theological seminary you say you are a
духовную семинарию вот ты говоришь ты
Christian Christian Yes a Christian
христианин христин Да вот христианин
should know every Christian should
должен знать каждый христианин должен
know the 10 commandments name at least five
знать 10 заповедей назви Хотя бы пять
good do not kill do not steal Do not envy
хорошо не убивай не кради Не завидуй
no
нету
ayyy no Do not envy there is such on
аййй нету Не завидуй такое есть по
google Yes do not Switch God's commandment
гуглите Да не Переключай заповедь Божья
Do not envy do not
Не завидуй не
Switch Give me more  The third commandment
Переключай Давай ещё третью заповедь
is called Do not envy it  commandment you can
называй а Не завидуй это заповедь можете
take a walk please
погулять пожалуйста
continue ok Honor only the true
дальше хорошо Почитай только истинного
God ok
Бога хорошо
ha don't envy all the same you should
ха не завида всё-таки вам стоит
continue bend your finger No then now you
дальше загни палец Нет потом сейчас назв
'll look at the name Look Then
посмотришь Посмотришь Потом
let's go ok Well actually don't create an
давай хорошо Ну собственно не создавай
idol don't make an idol Yes okay peace
кумира не сотвори се кумира Да окей мира
and Don't envy because it is
и Не завидуй потому что это
commandment let's give another
заповедь давай другую
commandment what is
заповедь что ри
hard for you commandments to google in your head
тяжело ти заповеди на гуглить в голове
if what in Christianity the main thing is Faith Faith
если что в христианстве главно Вера Вера
In what let's give here commandments Well commandments
Во что давай вот заповеди Ну заповеди
Let's give What else
Давай Какие ещё
try what again a couple more
попробуй что что ещё раз ещё пару
commandments
заповедей
I told you Don't envy you don't want to
я вам сказал Не завидуй вы не хотите
google don't want to find out  What are we
гуглить не хотите узнавать О чём
talking about Let Come on, come on, except Don't
разговор Пусть Давай давай кроме Не
be jealous, can you name something else
завидуй ещё что-то можешь назвать
and that's it, Christianization has passed, the
и всё христианизация прошла мальца
main thing is Faith Faith In something that I invented for myself,
главное Вера Вера Во что-то что Сам себе
yes Aloe Vera Let's
придумал да Алое Вера Давай нормально
talk normally, you and Russia Yes, that's how I
поговорим вы с россие Да я так
understand it Yes, I understood it, contract soldier,
понимаю Да с россие понял контрактник
conscript  urgent
срочник сроч
And those who are pilots there is a plane I don't know
А те кто лётчик там самолётик я не знаю
how Well just Let's go military  Let
как Ну просто Давайте военные ещё на
's stop here I realized something it's
этом остановимся понял что-то у тебя
very light where you are And this is you I thought you were
светло очень ты где А это ты Я думал ты
outside I thought it was the sun what brought you to the
на улице думал солнце что тебя привело в
chat Yes yes yes this is a street this is a street this is a
чат Да да да это улица это улица это
street And this is you somewhere in the Far East
улица А это ты где-то на Дальнем Востоке
yes yes yes  yes and you communicate with the World Cup
да да да да а ЧМ общаешься что тебя
what brought you to just communicate
привело что просто общаюсь
here no conscripts are
вот не бо срочников на
not sent to their conscripts with in the beginning
сво срочников не отправляют с в начале
they were sent I have friends who were there with being
отправляли у меня знакомые были там на с
conscripts And now they don't send
будучи срочникам А сейчас не отправляют
now they send Belgorod Well the border
сейчас отправляют Белгород Ну граница
Voronezh so there is the border Belgorod there is also
Воронеж так там граница Белгород там ещё
God willing
дай Боже
they fly in Well, I know Well, they give Well, I do
прилетают Ну я знаю Да ну придают Ну я
n't know They don't send from the Aerospace Forces They send from the infantry
не знаю с ВКС не отправляют с пехоты
What
по что тебя
interests you Well, nothing at all You just
интересует да ничего вообще Просто ты
consider yourself an
считаешь себя
occupier Why don't I consider myself an occupier Why
оккупант а почему не считаю а а почему я
should I consider myself an occupier I'm not a contract soldier I'm
должен себе считать Я же не контрактник
not going to sign a contract and  I
контракт подписывать не собираюсь и не
wasn't going to go to s I wasn't
собирался вот на с ехать я тоже не
going to either And if they take me away
собирался А если возьмут отправ вот
somehow Well, how can I get away
как-то так Ну как отпра кто меня может
Well, you have people
Ну у вас как бы я говорю да вот там люди
who think about the fact that everything  they will go
которые думают о том то что все поедут
Well, like, everyone will go, this is such a myth
Ну типа все поедут это такой знаете миф
that is currently in existence Mobi,
который сейчас в данный момент есть Моби
these are purely
эти чисто вот
these, they go there and
эти идут там
fight, so they are like, there are people who have
воюют вот им как бы там людей которых
no money, yes, they cannot
бабок нет денег да они не могут себе
earn money for themselves Yes, because they
заработать Да потому что они ничего не
do nothing at all,
делают вообще
they are like a brain
мозг они как бы
there they are not going to go to the slo It's
там не не собираются ехать на сло
cool something like
Прикольно вот как-то
this
так
[music]
[музыка]
yeah yeah what do you have there is true that like now
угу что там у вас правда что типа сейчас
in the army there are a lot of Tajiks
в армии много таджиков
conscripts who conscripts Tajiks who
срочников кого срочников таджиков кого
Tajiks cadets
таджиков кадетов
Tajiks and Tajiks No, the first time
таджиков а таджиков Нет первый раз
I heard that,
слышал
I didn't hear Tajiks  I've never seen
вот не таджиков я ни разу не видел
conscripts, but
срочников а с всего такая
I've only been told this information, yes, guys,
информация мне рассказывали да ребята
there are already a lot of Tajiks in your
что там таджика уже очень много у вас в
army, I don't know. Well, like, here we are. Out of how many of the
армии не знаю Ну типа вот у нас Из
n people, there were two, two non-
скольки из п человек было два два не
Russians, two
русских два
Dagestanis. And you, you know where you are.  like
дагестанца А ты ты где-то шаришь ты типа
what are you doing in the unit all by yourself
что сам вообще там в часть
that you go alone Usually I thought the
что ты один ходишь Обычно я думал
army I thought the army like In short,
армия Я думал армия типа Все короче
outfit - what does outfit mean - this is
наряд - это что означает наряд - это
Clothes Well, outfit Well, you know, did you serve in the army
Одежда Ну наряд Ну вот знаете Вы в армии
at all  no No well outfit - I
служили вообще не Не ну наряд - это я
know that costumes outfit Well outfit no no
знаю костюмы наряд Ну наряд не нет
daily outfit daily outfit
суточный наряд суточный наряд несёт
serves to maintain internal
службу для поддержания внутреннего
order But at some point or there or
порядка А вот на какой-то либо там либо
in the company to maintain order And I'm on outfit
в роте порядок поддерживать А я в наряд
in the company And in the mouth it is necessary not in the company  And in the mouth
в роте А во рту надо не в роте А во рту
not in the mouth the company I mean the company is a
не во рту рота В смысле рота - это
room I thought I understood the order in the company
помещение Я думал порядок в роте понял
Duma not
Дума не не
quite So what are you Well I'm not on What is
совсем Так а что ты Ну я не по В чём
the point of your going what And I I'm on patrol
суть твоя ходить что А я я в патруле
patrolling
патрулируют
not I'm a conscript I'm not a policeman I  patrols
не я срочник Я не полице я патрули
patrol Well patrols I go In short I just
патруль Ну патрули хожу Короче просто
go around the territory watching so that there
хожу по территории наблюдаю чтобы не
are no civilians in a certain
было гражданских лиц на определённой
territory and
территории и
that's it What's the point
всё В чём суть ходить
just walking and here you don't need to ask questions
просто а тут вопросы не надо задавать
this is the army this is the Russian army what why
это армия это Российская армия что зачем
at all
вообще
Duma Yes they just said to walk 500 at
Дума Да просто сказали ходить по 500
night Well how  During the day two And at night for p
ночью Ну как Днём по два Да и ночью по п
That's because sleep who cares of these
Вот потому что сон кому разница из этих
people not military why
из э людей не военных зачем туда
come there Who will
приходить Кто
come Well I don't know just to look to
придёт Ну я не знаю просто посмотреть
stare I don't know here there's a thorn hanging
поглазеть я не знаю тутто колючка висит
suddenly well you know It's a human factor
вдруг ну знаете Это человеческий фактор
just a human factor When you
просто человеческий фактор Когда ты
you go and you have it written there Stop there
идёшь А у тебя там написано Стой там
Forbidden zone Yes there is a military facility and
Запретная зона Да там военный объект А
you just want to go there Probably to get in
ты просто туда захочешь Наверное полесть
I don't know Well I don't know what people generally
я не знаю Ну я не знаю чем люди вообще
think when they want to get in Yes there were
думают когда они хотят проникать Да
military
военные
facilities yes yes there were and what they did Well
объекты да да были и что делали Ну в
basically basically  children Yes, nothing,
основном в основном дете Да ничего
they were just driven away, what to
просто прогоняли их что
shout against the civilian population
покричать против гражданского населения
Well, against I mean, they came in conditionally Yes, there are
Ну против В смысле вот зашли условно Да
children there, 8 to 10 years old, I will take
там дети по 8 по 10 лет я там буду по
turns shooting at them So you
очередью по ним стрелять Так у тебя и
dont even have a weapon, how will you do it, you
оружия нету как ты будешь ты же без
walk around without a weapon Well, a weapon  there is No well there
оружия ходишь Ну оружие есть Не ну
is a weapon It's just I don't take it
оружие есть Оно просто я его не беру
here Well that's what I'm saying what you
сюда Ну то Я же говорю то что ты
'll do you know they'll say Good
сделаешь понимаешь те скажет Добрый
evening
вечер
to them Well I'm like that well basically there's
им Да ну я как бы это ну в основном тут
no one here well like there were moments from civilians
никого нету ну типа из гражданских были
when they came in like that  well
там моменты когда заходили типа вот ну
they were immediately chased away and all
их сразу просто прогоняли и всё
that stuff It's cool and what are you guarding
такого Прикольно а а что ты охраняешь
there what are some tanks missiles I do
там что та какие-то Танки ракеты Я
n't understand something well no not tanks not
что-то не понимаю ну нет не танки не
missiles Well I won't say what I'm
ракеты Ну я не буду говорить что я
guarding because But it's unknown where
охраняю потому что А вот неизвестно куда
my  speech now can get into a lie
моя речь сечас может попасть вру
you shoot normally we say like well I
снимаете нормально говорим типа ну я се
go out after work so talk to
выхожу после работы так поговорить с
people normally with you speak nothing like
людьми нормально с тобой говори ниче
that there is no secret I'm just territory I
такого нет секре я просто территорию Я
guard the territory And that's all well but wushu on
территорию охраняю И всё ну а вот ушу на
yours I just can't understand well who do you
вашей Я просто не могу понять ну кем ты
serve  what do you have in your
служишь что у вас в
territory well the territory is just a
территории ну территория просто
gas station gas station fuel I don't know do you know
заправка заправка ГСМ Я не знаю знаете
what a gas station is gas station is where
что такое заправка заправка это там где
ninety pi
девяносто пй
is fuel yes exactly like that otherwise like you're a
это топливо да именно так а то типа ты
gas station attendant No I'm not a gas station attendant
заправщик Нет я не заправщик заправщик
these are special people here Well as it is
это специальные люди сюда Ну как есть
there are civilians who  work in the
есть гражданские люди которые работают в
Ministry of Defense who are civilians, I
Минобороны которые гражданских профе
just go and so that there are no
просто хожу и чтобы чтобы людей не было
civilians here, ordinary people, not those who
гражданских тут обычных людей не которые
work, but those who just want to
работают да а которые просто там захотят
look there and that's it, that's all, that's the
посмотреть и всё вот и всё в этом
essence of my outfit. That is, it
заключается суть моего наряда То есть
turns out. And what is the essence of Service in the
получается А в чём тогда суть Службы в
Army then?  just go as a
Армии просто ходить
security guard Well, not always I still work on equipment
охранником Ну не всегда я ещё На технике
I have category C there is this in
работаю у меня категория C есть это в
Coma I can transfer something there
Кома я могу там перевести что-то гравий
bring gravel sand transported That's how it is Here to
привести песок перевез Вот так вот Вот
serve a security guard and a driver yes Well, yes,
обслужить охранник и водитель да Ну да
essentially it is Well  more of a security guard Than a
по сути это Ну больше охранник Чем
driver because you don't always need to
водитель потому что не всегда нужно там
bring something there It's cool and it's so
что-то привести Прикольно а у вас так
light where you are it's just 12 at night where I am
светло это у меня просто сейчас 12 ночи
And what time is it where you are And I'm in Primorye I'm in
А у вас сколько А я в Приморье Я в
Primorye It's 7 am where I am Primorye - What
Приморье У меня 7 утра Приморье - Это
is Primorsky Krai Far  Vostok
такое Приморский край Дальний Восток
Dalnik
Дальник
Vostok is a city
Восток город есть
there Well, yes, here is Vladivostok Well, the Far
там Ну да вот Владивосток Ну Дальний
East I mean, they say this for the western
Восток В смысле это говорят за западную
part of Russia there for the western what I mean
часть России там за западную что я несу
for the eastern part of Russia closer to Japan
за Восточную часть России ближе к Японии
there except for Vladivostok there is only China
там там кроме Владивостока только Китай
there it seems there are no
там вроде нет городов
more cities Well, yes, Khabarovsk is Vladivostok
больше Ну да Хабаровск есть Владивосток
Khabarovsk Blagoveshchensk many cities Well,
Хабаровск Благовещенск много городов Ну
what city are you from?
а ты из какого
From
города с
Vladivostok? Are you in Vladivostok? There are
Владивостока это ты во владивосто там же
ships on the
корабли по
Tamr. Well, I am there where the
тамр ну я там где суш
land is, it is confusing. In short,
суша запутано Короче так
it is so unclear. Well, this is the army, here, as if, you dont
непонятно Ну это армия тут как бы не
have to think.
надо думать
The Russians are for a dog. Everything is for you. It
российс за собака тут за тебя всё
was invented. An ordinary dog.  so I mean
Придумано обычная собака так В смысле
if you don't have to think for you I'll come
если не надо думать за тебя всё приду
if they come up with something for you I wo
если те ска за тебя придумали на те
n't go to them So what if they send you What
не поеду Так а Если отправят Что
you will do
сделаешь
how how can they send me Well, well,
как как меня могут отправить Ну вот Ну
it's even logical to think Well, well,
это даже логически подумать Ну как ну
well, they won't send Yes, you have some kind of
вот не отправят Да у тебя какой-то там
peak dog like barking
пик дог типа гавкает
Well, alabai, alabai Show me, damn, this is
Ну алабай алабай Покажи блин это
healthy, you're not afraid that he'll
здоровый вас таки тебе не страшно что он
break free
вырвется
Well, yes No, and what  she's used to it Well, the fact
Ну да Нет а что она это привыкшая Ну то
that we are like this she knows us she is
что мы как бы это она знает нас она это
Unclean
Нечистая
she is
она
Dana Well, show me how she looks
Дана Ну покажи как она выглядит
cool No I can't Well, just a
прикольно Нет не могу Ну собаку просто
dog just a dog Well I'm standing I'm standing There are
просто собаку Ну я стою я стою Там как
cameras standing there so as not to get watered I
бы камеры стоят стою там чтобы не полить
understood date
понял дате
Well  well I'll take the phone at
Ну ну заберу телефон как
least Okay fine I'll go
минимум Ладно хорошо Пойду
let's write to my Telegram right now
давай пись на мий Telegram прямо зараз
axis VN
ось ВН
apok this is very and very important YouTube is busy
апок це дуже и дуже важливо YouTube заня
with us through scarg ORV in your ban and very
нас через скарг ОРВ в твий бан и дуже
many videos are not shown to people sometimes do not
багато вдео не показуе людям вчасно не
show information about streams so that
показуе информация про стримы тому для
Mali  the operational link
того щоб Мали оперативный звязок
is written right now and Popik is there
пишиться прямо зараз а Попик там в
telegrams okrim video tezh tsikava and
телеграми окрим видео ще теж цикава и
useful information and we are obliged to you
корисна информация и мы повинни з вами
trimati constant operational links
тримати постийний оперативный звязок
independently in that chi will show you about this
незалежно в того чи покаже вам про це
YouTube Slava ukraini
YouTube Слава украини
letter ah
пись ah